

www.franc.ly | hi@franc.ly | 347-371-1984

Franc Camps-Febrer is a Barcelona-born, New York-based front end engineer and designer specialized in data visualization. He brings together his background as a scientist and his life-long interests in design and storytelling to create interactive applications that help navigate complex information and narratives in beautiful and immersive ways, providing delightful experiences in a variety of contexts and formats.

Education

2014

SCHOOL FOR POETIC COMPUTATION

Residency and intensive school on art, design, code and creative technology.

New York City

2013

NYU's ITP CAMP

Summer intensive at the Interactive Telecommunications Program in Design and Technology. New York University, New York City

2002-2007

BSc IN THEORETICAL PHYSICS

5-year Bachelor of Science degree 1 year at Biophysics department of the Université Paul Sabatier, Toulouse, France. Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona, Barcelona

Work experience

2012 - Dec 2015

KNEWTON Software engineer - Front end.

Previous: Data visualization designer and engineer Knewton Data Arts Lab / Front-end Team

New York City

2012 - 2014

GOTEO Data visualization engineer, product designer.

Data visualization consultant for an opensource, social focused crowdfunding platform.

Barcelona (remote)

2011

INFOGRAPHICS Designer & web developer

Data visualization designer and web developer for clients such as Cirque de Soleil or Microsoft.

New York City

2011

NYU CENTER FOR BRAIN IMAGING

Research Assistant

COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY, DEP OF PSYCHOLOGY

Research Assistant

2008

CHARITE UNIVERSITATSMEDIZIN (BERLIN) Lab technician

Skills and interests

DESIGN VISUALIZATION CREATIVE TECH		ENGINEERIN FRONT END & 0	_	LANGUAGES		LEARNING INTERESTS	
d3.js		HTML, CSS, JS		English		UX Design	
openFrameworks		SASS, CSS3	****	Spanish		Product management	
Processing		Node		Catalan	****	Android / iOS development	
Adobe CS		Git		French			
Arduino		Backbone, React		German		OTHER INTERESTS	S
		Dust, Jade, Handlebars		Portuguese			_
		Jest, Mocha, Nightwatch				World politics	
						Capoeira	
		. Janen, sava ana o				Sociology of art and culture	

Other personal projects